<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom" xmlns:content="http://purl.org/rss/1.0/modules/content/">
  <channel>
    <title>Mohit Dodhia</title>
    <link>https://dodhia.in/</link>
    <description>Recent content on Mohit Dodhia</description>
    <image>
      <url>https://dodhia.in/%3Clink%20or%20path%20of%20image%20for%20opengraph,%20twitter-cards%3E</url>
      <link>https://dodhia.in/%3Clink%20or%20path%20of%20image%20for%20opengraph,%20twitter-cards%3E</link>
    </image>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <language>en-us</language>
    <lastBuildDate>Thu, 06 Apr 2023 20:37:35 +0530</lastBuildDate><atom:link href="https://dodhia.in/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    <item>
      <title>Links</title>
      <link>https://dodhia.in/links/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 06 Aug 2023 10:46:33 +0530</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://dodhia.in/links/</guid>
      <description>A compilation of links I found interesting.
Blogs  The worst mistake of computer science This time, it feels different Reading the Mahabharata by the Tungabhadra Scaling with common sense Unpopular tech/software engineering opinions - 2022 edition Leave Scrum to Rugby, I Like Getting Stuff Done Your Manager Can’t Code? They Shouldn’t Be Your Manager  </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Social Media Rant</title>
      <link>https://dodhia.in/blog/social-media-rant/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 06 Apr 2023 20:37:35 +0530</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://dodhia.in/blog/social-media-rant/</guid>
      <description>These days opening Social Media feels like visiting a zoo, where you wander around aimlessly seeing what other animals are up to. The life of those animals don&amp;rsquo;t affect yours in the slightest yet you look at them for a few minutes and continue to the next enclosement until you run out of them, in which case you exit after spending a chunk of your time. I see little to no benefit in this pointless loitering.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Good Start to 2023</title>
      <link>https://dodhia.in/blog/good-start-to-2023/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 27 Feb 2023 18:46:57 +0530</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://dodhia.in/blog/good-start-to-2023/</guid>
      <description>The year started with an unexpected promotion, considering I was promoted just 6 months ago. This, in my eyes, makes the stint at Infosys quite successful as I have been promoted twice while being a recipient of 2 awards, all in less than 2 years.
The days that followed were filled with kite-flying and hogging Undhiyu with family. It has been a while since we had such a large family gathering, and their presence made my favourite festival even more enjoyable.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Danke Seb</title>
      <link>https://dodhia.in/blog/danke-seb/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 20 Nov 2022 23:57:19 +0530</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://dodhia.in/blog/danke-seb/</guid>
      <description>TL;DR: Sebastian Vettel has retired from Formula One and I am very sad.
 To give you some perspective, I started watching Formula One after the summer break of the 2018 season. Being a new follower of the sport, I was busy learning and remembering names, rules and concepts that were being thrown my way. As the season progressed towards the finale, I couldn&amp;rsquo;t help but naturally get drawn to two drivers: Charles Leclerc and Sebastian Vettel.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Migrating to GitHub Pages</title>
      <link>https://dodhia.in/blog/migrating-to-github-pages/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 05 Oct 2022 12:11:28 +0530</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://dodhia.in/blog/migrating-to-github-pages/</guid>
      <description>TL;DR: The website logistically didn&amp;rsquo;t make sense, especially with this blog being hosted on GitHub Pages and only accessible through the website.
 After a good deal of consideration, I finally pulled the plug on my website which was hosted on the domain www.mxhit.dev. This website was up and running for only a year but the decision to migrate was based on first principles of software engineering &amp;ndash; this should have been my approach from the beginning however my reasons at the time were valid.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>JavaScript Rant</title>
      <link>https://dodhia.in/blog/javascript-rant/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 16 Aug 2022 22:14:59 +0530</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://dodhia.in/blog/javascript-rant/</guid>
      <description>If you were to believe the Tech Twitter gyaandus, JavaScript is probably the best language out there which can be used for all your programming needs. I feel this is misleading and enforces why you should always do your due diligence instead of blindly accepting their opinions.
JavaScript, like many programming languages, was created to solve a problem. A solution for a specific problem or a set of similar problems cannot be used for all the problems you will encounter in the tech industry.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Charlatans of Web3</title>
      <link>https://dodhia.in/blog/charlatans-of-web3/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 29 May 2022 14:23:56 +0530</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://dodhia.in/blog/charlatans-of-web3/</guid>
      <description>Web 3.0, commonly referred to as Web3, has become quite the catchphrase on the internet. For those of you who don&amp;rsquo;t know what Web3 is, it&amp;rsquo;s a proposed iteration of the World Wide Web based on the Blockchain technology. Tech communities across several platforms have been bandwagoning it as if it will be the ultimate form of the Internet that fuels our lives. I don&amp;rsquo;t feel this way; in fact I have a lot of concerns due to the nature of Blockchain technologies &amp;ndash; more on this later.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Exploring ECMAScript6</title>
      <link>https://dodhia.in/blog/exploring-ecmascript6/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 28 Mar 2022 17:47:19 +0530</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://dodhia.in/blog/exploring-ecmascript6/</guid>
      <description>In my almost three years of experience as a Java developer, I have hardly been exposed to working with front-end technologies. A little JSP here, a tad bit of CSS there, and the occasional $(&amp;quot;#div&amp;quot;).modal() while debugging to check whether my modals were showing up correctly or not. In conclusion, very elementary. However, I switched my job after two years and currently I am working with a legacy application that employs Core Java for the back-end and Angular.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Brief Stint with the #100DaysOfCode Challenge</title>
      <link>https://dodhia.in/blog/brief-stint-with-100doc/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 17 Nov 2021 19:30:48 +0530</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://dodhia.in/blog/brief-stint-with-100doc/</guid>
      <description>The easiest part about the #100DaysOfCode Challenge is taking up the challenge. The harder part is committing to it while coming up with new ideas for each day; it’s both exciting and daunting. I experienced this for the first time when I publicly committed to the challenge on Twitter. It is generally advised to have a rough map of ideas ready when taking up the challenge but I took a different approach of establishing rules simply because I need to fall in line with them while developing things every day.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>About Me</title>
      <link>https://dodhia.in/about/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://dodhia.in/about/</guid>
      <description>I am currently working at Infosys as a Technology Analyst.
I graduated with a Bachelor&amp;rsquo;s in Computer Science and Engineering from SRM Institute of Science and Technology, Chennai in 2019.
 Why I became a Software Engineer? I would consider my introduction to programming through MSW Logo &amp;ndash; something about making different shapes by typing a few commands had blown me away as a child. It was not until 9th grade, when I was introduced to Java, that I truly started enjoying writing code.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Projects</title>
      <link>https://dodhia.in/projects/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://dodhia.in/projects/</guid>
      <description>This page contains a list of projects (finished and ongoing) developed over a period of time. Demo links may not be available for all projects listed here.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Proof of Work</title>
      <link>https://dodhia.in/proofofwork/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://dodhia.in/proofofwork/</guid>
      <description>[Last updated on 07/08/2023]</description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>
