<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>javascript on Mohit Dodhia</title>
    <link>https://dodhia.in/tags/javascript/</link>
    <description>Recent content in javascript on Mohit Dodhia</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <language>en-us</language>
    <lastBuildDate>Wed, 05 Oct 2022 12:11:28 +0530</lastBuildDate><atom:link href="https://dodhia.in/tags/javascript/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    <item>
      <title>Migrating to GitHub Pages</title>
      <link>https://dodhia.in/blog/migrating-to-github-pages/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 05 Oct 2022 12:11:28 +0530</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://dodhia.in/blog/migrating-to-github-pages/</guid>
      <description>TL;DR: The website logistically didn&amp;rsquo;t make sense, especially with this blog being hosted on GitHub Pages and only accessible through the website.
 After a good deal of consideration, I finally pulled the plug on my website which was hosted on the domain www.mxhit.dev. This website was up and running for only a year but the decision to migrate was based on first principles of software engineering &amp;ndash; this should have been my approach from the beginning however my reasons at the time were valid.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>JavaScript Rant</title>
      <link>https://dodhia.in/blog/javascript-rant/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 16 Aug 2022 22:14:59 +0530</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://dodhia.in/blog/javascript-rant/</guid>
      <description>If you were to believe the Tech Twitter gyaandus, JavaScript is probably the best language out there which can be used for all your programming needs. I feel this is misleading and enforces why you should always do your due diligence instead of blindly accepting their opinions.
JavaScript, like many programming languages, was created to solve a problem. A solution for a specific problem or a set of similar problems cannot be used for all the problems you will encounter in the tech industry.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Exploring ECMAScript6</title>
      <link>https://dodhia.in/blog/exploring-ecmascript6/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 28 Mar 2022 17:47:19 +0530</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://dodhia.in/blog/exploring-ecmascript6/</guid>
      <description>In my almost three years of experience as a Java developer, I have hardly been exposed to working with front-end technologies. A little JSP here, a tad bit of CSS there, and the occasional $(&amp;quot;#div&amp;quot;).modal() while debugging to check whether my modals were showing up correctly or not. In conclusion, very elementary. However, I switched my job after two years and currently I am working with a legacy application that employs Core Java for the back-end and Angular.</description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>
